
FINAL IMPLEMENTATION HANDOFFStyleAtlas HomepageRemaining Fixes After Live ReviewMAIN INSTRUCTIONFix only the issues listed in this document. Keep the parts that already work. Do not redesign the homepage again, add new sections, or replace approved copy without a clear reason.Live page reviewed: 26 August 2026What is already correctThe hero search no longer overlaps the next section.The page is shorter and easier to scan.Categories and cities are combined.How It Works uses three clear steps.Trust and verification use two audience cards.Explore Opportunities uses a compact two-by-two grid.The business call-to-action has the correct two buttons.Main conversion links point to working destinations.What still needs workFeatured Professionals is missing.The desktop footer is too tall and visually unbalanced.The Subscribe button text is too small and has poor contrast.The newsletter form is too narrow.The hero is taller than necessary.The hero search still contains too many filters.Some verification wording may promise more than the process proves.The business call-to-action has too much empty space on the right.1. Working rules for the AI agentDO NOT SKIP THISCreate a staging copy and take a backup before editing. Do not publish until every item in the final checklist passes.Do not rebuild the page from scratch.Do not change the logo, brand colours, global typography, URLs, pricing, accounts, directory data or SEO settings.Do not change sections that already work unless this document asks for a small adjustment.Do not invent professionals, reviews, listing counts, verification checks or testimonials.Do not remove working search logic. Simplify only the visible fields in the hero.Use real profile data for Featured Professionals.Test the final page at 320px, 360px, 390px, 430px, 768px, 1024px, 1366px and 1440px.Return screenshots and a completion report before publishing.Required final section countDesktop orderMobile order1. Hero1. Hero2. Categories and Cities2. Categories and Cities3. Featured Professionals3. Featured Professionals4. How It Works4. How It Works5. Trust and Verification5. Trust and Verification6. Explore Opportunities6. Business CTA7. Business CTA7. Footer8. FooterMOBILE RULEDo not show Explore Opportunities as a homepage section on mobile. Keep Marketplace, Jobs, Events, Schools and Journal available in the mobile menu and footer.2. Add the missing Featured Professionals sectionPRIORITY 1Place this new section directly after Categories and Cities and before How It Works. This section is required because the homepage currently talks about professionals without showing any real professionals.Exact section copyProfessionals worth discovering.Explore selected talent from across Nigeria.Desktop layoutShow exactly four real professional cards in one row at 1280px and above.Use two cards per row between 768px and 1279px.Keep the section inside the same maximum content width as Categories and Cities.Use 88px to 104px top and bottom padding.Add one link below the cards: Browse all professionals.Mobile layoutShow three real profiles in a horizontal swipe row.Show one full card and a small part of the next card so visitors know they can swipe.Do not stack many large profile cards vertically.Use 56px to 64px top and bottom padding.Keep the Browse all professionals link visible below the cards.Each profile card must containA real profile image in a consistent 4:5 ratio.Professional name or business name.Category.City.A verification badge only when the profile is truly verified.A View profile link or button.Do not includeLong biographies.More than one line of speciality text.Fake reviews or ratings.Made-up verification badges.Stock people who do not have StyleAtlas profiles.Section order:Categories and CitiesFeatured ProfessionalsHow It Works3. Correct the desktop footerPRIORITY 2The current footer is about 711px tall. The newsletter sits under the first column, leaving a large empty area on the right. Rebuild the footer into one balanced top row and one compact bottom row.3.1 Required desktop structureUse one five-column top row:Column 1: logo, short description and newsletter.Column 2: Directory.Column 3: Explore.Column 4: For Business.Column 5: Company.Place copyright and legal links in one bottom row.3.2 Footer measurementsDesktop maximum content width: 1240px.Top padding: 72px.Bottom padding: 28px.Column gap: 40px to 64px.Footer bottom row margin-top: 48px to 56px.Footer target height: 480px to 560px.Remove fixed height and min-height values that create empty space.footer {  height: auto;  min-height: 0;  padding: 72px 0 28px;}.footer-top {  display: grid;  grid-template-columns: 1.45fr 1fr 1fr 1fr 1fr;  gap: 48px;  align-items: start;}.footer-bottom {  margin-top: 56px;  padding-top: 24px;}3.3 Newsletter form correctionSet the form width to 100% with a maximum width of 420px.Show Email address fully above the field.Add 8px between the label and input row.Input and button height: 48px.Input text and placeholder: at least 13px.Subscribe button text: 13px to 14px, bold and near-black.Button width: at least 100px.Do not clip the label, input or button at any width..newsletter { width: 100%; max-width: 420px; }.newsletter label { display: block; margin-bottom: 8px; color: #ffffff; font-size: 13px; font-weight: 600; }.newsletter-row { display: flex; width: 100%; }.newsletter input { min-width: 0; flex: 1; height: 48px; font-size: 13px; }.newsletter button { flex: 0 0 auto; min-width: 100px; height: 48px; background: #d4a373; color: #111111; font-size: 13px; font-weight: 700; }3.4 Footer text contrastLink colour: #cfc7bd or a colour with equal contrast.Link hover and keyboard-focus colour: #ffffff.Column headings: white or near-white.Do not use text smaller than 13px on mobile.Make keyboard focus clearly visible.4. Correct the mobile footerMOBILE GOALThe mobile footer must be compact. It must not copy the wide desktop columns and stack them into a very long page.Required mobile orderLogo and short description.Newsletter label and form.Directory accordion.Explore accordion.For Business accordion.Company accordion.Copyright and legal links.Mobile rulesUse one column below 768px.Use 48px top padding and 24px bottom padding.Use accordion buttons at least 48px tall.All accordion panels must be closed by default, except one may be open if required.Do not leave blank grid columns or hidden elements that still reserve height.Do not use absolute positioning for newsletter controls.Legal links may wrap, but they must not overflow horizontally.The footer must end shortly after the copyright and legal links. No large black empty block should remain.@media (max-width: 767px) {  footer { padding: 48px 20px 24px; height: auto; min-height: 0; }  .footer-top { display: block; }  .footer-newsletter { margin-bottom: 32px; }  .footer-nav { display: block; }  .footer-bottom { margin-top: 32px; padding-top: 20px; }}Mobile footer testOpen the page at 320px wide.Scroll to the footer.Confirm Email address is fully visible.Confirm the Subscribe button text is easy to read.Open and close every accordion.Confirm no footer content overlaps.Confirm no horizontal scrolling.Confirm no empty black area appears after the legal links.5. Reduce the hero heightKEEP THE DESIGNDo not redesign the hero. The image, headline and brand styling already work. Only reduce unnecessary vertical space.Desktop adjustmentReduce hero height from about 825px to 680px to 720px.Use top padding around 72px and bottom padding around 56px.Keep the search form fully inside the hero.Keep at least 48px between the search form and the bottom edge.Do not use negative margins, translateY or a negative bottom value.Keep the image subject properly framed after reducing height..home-hero {  position: relative;  min-height: 680px;  padding: 72px 0 56px;  overflow: hidden;}.home-hero__search {  position: relative;  inset: auto;  transform: none;  margin-top: 28px;}Mobile adjustmentUse a single-column hero.Use 48px to 56px top padding and 40px to 48px bottom padding.Do not display the full multi-field search form.Show one Find professionals button and one List your business link.Keep mobile headline size between 40px and 46px.Do not let the hero image push the first content section too far down the page.6. Simplify the hero searchCONVERSION CORRECTIONThe current desktop form fits, but it asks for keyword, category, location and speciality before the visitor has started. Reduce the visible choices.Desktop search fieldsField 1: What do you need?Field 2: Location.Button: Search.Move Category and Speciality to the directory results page or place them under a More filters control.Search behavior that must remain workingKeyword only.Location only.Keyword and location together.Empty search opens the directory or shows helpful choices.Search button works with mouse, touch and keyboard.Existing query parameters and results filtering are preserved.Mobile search behaviorDo not squeeze desktop fields into the mobile hero.Use one full-width Find professionals button.The button may open the directory search page or an accessible search panel.If a panel opens, provide a clear close button and return focus correctly.7. Correct verification wordingACCURACY RULEUse only claims that match the real StyleAtlas review process. Do not promise quality, safety or customer satisfaction unless StyleAtlas checks and guarantees those things.Customer cardHeading: Find with confidence.Copy: Explore reviewed profiles and portfolios.Button: Find professionalsProfessional cardHeading: Stand out as verified.Copy: Complete our review and earn the verification badge.Button: Learn about verificationRemove or confirm these claimsEvery professional is vetted.We check identities and review portfolios before profiles go live.Verified status signals quality to customers.If all three statements are fully true and documented in the verification policy, they may remain. Otherwise use the safer approved copy above.8. Correct the Business CTA empty spaceChoose one solutionRecommended solutionAdd one premium image on the right side using a real StyleAtlas business or an approved campaign image.Keep the existing text and buttons on the left.Use a 45% text and 55% image split.Keep panel height between 360px and 440px.Alternative solutionKeep the black panel without an image, but reduce its height to 300px to 340px.Vertically center the text and buttons.Do not leave a large empty right side inside a tall panel.9. Final testing checklistPUBLISHING GATEDo not publish until every applicable item below is confirmed. If something cannot be completed, report it clearly instead of skipping it.â˜ Featured Professionals appears after Categories and Cities.â˜ Featured profiles use real data and real verification status.â˜ Desktop has seven content sections plus the footer.â˜ Mobile has six content sections plus the footer.â˜ Explore Opportunities is absent from the mobile homepage.â˜ The footer is no taller than needed and has no large empty area.â˜ Desktop footer uses one balanced five-column top row.â˜ Mobile footer uses compact accordions.â˜ Email address is fully visible.â˜ Subscribe text is at least 13px, bold and high contrast.â˜ Newsletter form does not clip or overflow.â˜ Hero height is reduced without cropping important image content.â˜ Hero search stays completely inside the hero.â˜ No negative margin creates overlap.â˜ Desktop hero shows only keyword and location, plus Search.â˜ Mobile hero does not show the full desktop search form.â˜ Verification copy matches the real policy.â˜ Business CTA has an image or a shorter height.â˜ No horizontal scrolling at any test width.â˜ All buttons and links work.â˜ All controls have visible keyboard focus.â˜ Images below the fold lazy-load.â˜ One H1 is used and heading order is logical.â˜ Desktop and mobile screenshots were reviewed before publishing.10. Required completion reportThe AI agent must return all of the following:Staging or preview URL.List of files, components or sections changed.Desktop screenshot at 1440px.Mobile screenshot at 390px.Screenshot of the corrected desktop footer.Screenshot of the corrected mobile footer.Final desktop and mobile section counts.Confirmation that the hero has no overlap.Confirmation that the newsletter form has no clipping or low-contrast text.List of every item that could not be completed and the reason.Statement confirming whether the live page was changed.FINAL COMMAND TO THE AGENTComplete every instruction in this document in one implementation pass. Do not stop after changing only the footer. Do not remove the Featured Professionals section to make the page shorter. Keep mobile shorter by hiding Explore Opportunities, not by removing conversion proof.LATEST LIVE INSPECTION OVERRIDEStrict Final Completion OrderUse this section together with all earlier instructions in this document.NO PARTIAL COMPLETIONDo not report this task as complete after fixing only the footer, only the hero, or only one screen size. Completion means every required correction passes the final checks and the requested screenshots are supplied.A. Problems confirmed on the live homepageItemLive resultRequired resultFooter link groupsBroken. Links run together with no visible spacing.Each link on its own line with 12px to 16px gap.Newsletter widthBroken. Form stretches about 1240px across the footer.Maximum width 420px inside the first footer column.Newsletter labelMissing. Email address is only a placeholder.Visible Email address label above the field.Subscribe textImproved, but still about 12px.13px to 14px, bold, dark text on gold.Featured ProfessionalsStill missing.Add after Categories and Cities.Hero heightStill about 825px.680px to 720px on desktop.Hero filtersStill four fields plus Search.Keyword, Location and Search only.Verification copyOld strong claims remain.Use approved safe wording unless every claim is documented.Explore sectionNow about 843px and has longer copy.520px to 650px with short approved copy.Business CTAFixed. Image now fills the right side.Keep this correction. Do not redesign it.Footer total heightImproved to about 537px.Keep between 480px and 560px.B. Fix the footer without breaking it againKeep the current reduced footer height.Keep the improved dark Subscribe text.Place the brand description and newsletter inside the first footer column.Keep Directory, Explore, For Business and Company as four separate columns.Make every navigation link a block item on its own line.Do not use inline links, a horizontal row, nowrap, or display: contents for footer lists.Limit the newsletter form to 420px. Do not let it span beneath all columns.Add a visible Email address label. Use Enter your email as the placeholder.Test the footer at desktop, tablet and mobile widths before moving to the next task..footer-top {  display: grid;  grid-template-columns: 1.45fr 1fr 1fr 1fr 1fr;  gap: 48px;  align-items: start;}.footer-column nav,.footer-column ul {  display: flex;  flex-direction: column;  align-items: flex-start;  gap: 14px;  margin: 0;  padding: 0;}.footer-column a,.footer-column li {  display: block;  width: fit-content;  white-space: normal;}.footer-newsletter,.footer-newsletter form {  width: 100%;  max-width: 420px;}.footer-newsletter label {  display: block;  margin-bottom: 8px;  color: #ffffff;  font-size: 13px;  font-weight: 600;}.footer-newsletter button {  min-width: 100px;  font-size: 13px;  font-weight: 700;  color: #111111;}C. Complete every skipped homepage correctionC1. Featured ProfessionalsAdd it directly after Categories and Cities.Heading: Professionals worth discovering.Supporting line: Explore selected talent from across Nigeria.Desktop: four real profiles in one row.Tablet: two cards per row.Mobile: three real profiles in a horizontal swipe row.Card content: image, real name or business, category, city, genuine verification status and View profile.Do not invent profiles, badges, reviews or ratings.C2. HeroKeep the current headline, image and visual direction.Reduce desktop height from about 825px to 680px to 720px.Keep the form fully inside the hero.Desktop visible fields: What do you need, Location and Search.Move Category and Speciality to results or More filters.Mobile: show Find professionals and List your business. Do not show the full desktop form.Do not use negative margins or transform values that can recreate overlap.C3. Verification wordingCustomer cardHeading: Find with confidence.Copy: Explore reviewed profiles and portfolios.Button: Find professionals.Professional cardHeading: Stand out as verified.Copy: Complete our review and earn the verification badge.Button: Learn about verification.CLAIM CONTROLKeep stronger statements only when the public verification policy proves that every listed professional receives those exact checks. Do not say verification guarantees quality, safety, pricing or satisfaction.C4. Explore OpportunitiesReplace the new long heading with: More from Nigerian fashion.Supporting line: Shop, learn and discover new opportunities.Keep the four compact cards: Marketplace, Jobs, Events and Schools.Keep the Journal as one small link below the cards.Desktop section height: 520px to 650px.Hide this homepage section below 768px. Keep the destinations in the mobile menu and footer.C5. Business CTAKeep the image that is now on the right.Keep the existing heading and two buttons.Do not remove the image or return the empty right side.Confirm the image does not crop faces or important clothing at any test width.D. Required implementation orderCreate or refresh the staging copy and confirm a restorable backup exists.Fix footer link spacing and newsletter width.Add the visible newsletter label and correct button size.Add Featured Professionals using real profile data.Reduce hero height and simplify visible search fields.Replace verification wording.Shorten Explore Opportunities and hide it on mobile.Keep the corrected Business CTA image.Test every required screen width.Capture proof screenshots.Return the completion report.Publish only if publication was explicitly authorized.E. Hard acceptance testâ˜ No footer words run together.â˜ Every footer link is individually clickable and keyboard focusable.â˜ Newsletter form is no wider than 420px on desktop.â˜ Email address appears as a visible label.â˜ Subscribe text is 13px or 14px, bold and high contrast.â˜ Desktop footer remains between 480px and 560px high.â˜ Mobile footer has no blank black area, clipping or horizontal scroll.â˜ Featured Professionals is present after Categories and Cities.â˜ All featured profiles are real and link to correct profiles.â˜ Desktop hero is no taller than 720px.â˜ Hero form never overlaps another element.â˜ Desktop hero shows only keyword, location and Search.â˜ Mobile hero does not show the full desktop form.â˜ Verification copy matches the real policy.â˜ Explore Opportunities is no taller than 650px on desktop.â˜ Explore Opportunities is hidden from the mobile homepage.â˜ Business CTA keeps its right-side image.â˜ Desktop has seven content sections plus the footer.â˜ Mobile has six content sections plus the footer.â˜ No horizontal scroll exists at 320px, 360px, 390px, 430px, 768px, 1024px, 1366px or 1440px.â˜ All buttons and links work.â˜ No new browser console error is caused by the homepage code.F. Proof required before saying completeStaging or live URL inspected after the changes.1440px full-page screenshot.390px full-page screenshot.Close desktop screenshot of the footer.Close mobile screenshot of the footer.Screenshot of Featured Professionals.Final desktop and mobile section counts.List of files, components or templates changed.List of every test above with Pass or Fail.Clear list of anything not completed and why.FINAL INSTRUCTION TO THE AI AGENTDo not use the word complete when any acceptance test is failed, skipped or unverified. Fix every failed item, retest the entire homepage, then supply all required proof in one final report.
